Painting Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Painting Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 2000
Yale University Arts Library
104
314 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Western painting. Some materials relating to Italian Renaissance painting located in the Yale University Art Gallery, 1100 Chapel Street, New Haven, Connecticut, 06520. For further detail, consult the Yale University Art Gallery location listing at the end of this finding aid.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Western painting. Some materials relating to Italian Renaissance painting located in the Yale University Art Gallery, 1100 Chapel Street, New Haven, Connecticut, 06520. For further detail, consult the Yale University Art Gallery location listing at the end of this finding aid.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by nationality individual artist name. Sub-divided primarily by location of the work. Some sections are preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Painting; Slides; Lantern slides; Reproductions
- Painting Egypt (Box 1)
  - Old Kingdom III-IV Dynasties (Box 1)
  - Middle Kingdom XI-XII Dynasties (Box 1)
  - Empire XVII-XX Dynasties (Box 1)
    - Deir-El-Bahri (Box 1)
    - Deir-El-Medineh (Box 1)
    - Thebes (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Apy (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Menna (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Nakht (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Nefertari (Box 1)
      - Tomb of Two Sculptors (Box 1)
    - Graeco-Roman, 332 BCE-640 CE (Box 1)
    - Near East (Box 1)
- Painting Eearly Medieval (Box 1)
  - Athens (Box 1)
  - Auxerre (Box 1)
  - Aquileia (Box 2)
  - Cappadocia, Turkey (Box 2)
  - Castelsperio (Box 2)
  - Chryssapha (Box 2)
  - Constantinople (Box 2)
    - Kariye Djami (Chora Church) (Box 2)
  - El Baghawat (Box 2)
  - Lagoudhera, Cyprus (Box 2)
  - Mals (Box 2)
  - Mistra (Box 2)
  - Mitylene (Box 2)
  - Mount Sinai (Box 2)
  - Munster-Mustair (Box 2)
  - Naples (Box 2)
  - Naturno-Germany (Box 2)
  - New Haven (Box 3)
  - Perustica, Turkey (Box 3)
  - Rome (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of Calixtus (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of Domitilla (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of SS. Peter and Marcellinus (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of Pretextatus (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of Priscilla (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of Torlonia (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of Via Latina (Box 3)
    - Catacomb of La Vigna Massimo (Box 3)
    - Hypogeum of Aurelii (Box 3)
    - S. Maria Antica (Box 3)
    - S. Clemente (Box 4)
  - Trier (Box 4)
- Painting Australia (Box 4)
  - ASHTON, Julian R., 1851- (Box 4)
  - BROADHURST, Francis J., 1914- (Box 4)
  - BUVELOT, Louis, 1814-1888 (Box 4)
  - CONDER, Charles, 1868-1909 (Box 4)
  - CONSTABLE, William, 1906- (Box 4)
  - CROW, Eileen (Box 4)
  - DAVIES, David, 1863-1939 (Box 4)
  - DOBELL, William, 1899- (Box 4)
  - DOWLING (Box 4)
  - DRYSDALE, George R., 1912- (Box 4)
  - EYRE, John (Box 4)
  - FEINT, Adrian, 1894- (Box 4)
  - GILL, Samuel T., ca. 1818-1880 (Box 4)
  - GLOVER, John, 1783-1838 (Box 4)
  - GOODCHILD, John C., 1898 (Box 4)
  - GOULD, W.B. (Box 4)
  - GRUNER, Elioth, 1882-1939 (Box 4)
  - HAXTON, Elaine (Box 4)
  - HERBERT, Harold, 1892- (Box 4)
  - HEYSEN, Hans (Box 4)
  - HILDER, Jesse J., 1881-1916 (Box 4)
  - JONES, Charles, 1878- (Box 4)
  - KING, Philip P., 1791-1856 (Box 4)
  - LAMBERT, George Washington, 1873-1930 (Box 4)
  - LINDSAY, Daryl, 1890- (Box 4)
  - McCUBBIN, Frederick, 1855-1917 (Box 4)
  - MacQUEEN, Kenneth, 1897- (Box 4)
  - MAINWARING, G.B., 1912- (Box 4)
  - MARTENS, Conrad, 1801-1878 (Box 4)
  - MOORE, John D. (Box 5)
  - NOLAN, Sidney (Box 5)
  - PARKINSON (Box 5)
  - PATTERSON, Ambrose, 1877- (Box 5)
  - POWER, Septimus, 1878- (Box 5)
  - PRESTON, Margaret (Box 5)
  - ROBERTS, Tom, 1856-1931 (Box 5)
  - ROPER, J. (Box 5)
  - SAINTHILL, Loudon, 1918- (Box 5)
  - SMITH, Peter F., 1913- (Box 5)
  - SMITH, Sydney D. (Box 5)
  - STRUTT, William (Box 5)
  - WAINEWRIGHT, Thomas G., 1794-1847 (Box 5)
  - WATLING, Thomas (Box 5)
  - WITHERS, Walter, 1854-1914 (Box 5)
- Painting Austria (Box 5)
  - ALT, Rudolf, 1812-1905 (Box 5)
  - ALTOMONTE, Bartholomaus, 1702-1749 (Box 5)
  - BERGL, Johann (Box 5)
  - BOECKL, Herbert (Box 5)
  - BRAND, Johannes Christian (Box 5)
  - FUHRICH, Joseph von, 1800-1876 (Box 5)
  - GERSTL, Richard, 1883-1908 (Box 5)
  - GRAN, Daniel, 1694-1757 (Box 5)
  - HAUSMANN, Raoul, 1886-1971 (Box 5)
  - KLIMT, Gustav, 1862-1918 (Box 5)
  - KOKOSCHKA, Oskar, 1886-1980 (Box 5–6)
  - KUBIN, Alfred, 1877-1959 (Box 6)
  - MAKART, Hans, 1840-1884 (Box 6)
  - MAULBERTSCHE, Franz, 1724-1796 (Box 6)
  - MOLL, Carl, 1861-1945 (Box 6)
  - SCHIELE, Egon, 1890-1918 (Box 6)
  - SCHONBERG, Arnold (Box 6)
  - SCHWIND, Moritz von, 1804-1871 (Box 6)
  - SEISNEGGER, Jacob (Box 6)
  - STEINLE, Johann Eduard von, 1810-1886 (Box 6)
  - TROGER, Paul, 1698-1762 (Box 6)
  - WALDMULLER, Ferdinand, 1793-1865 (Box 6)
- Painting Belgium (Box 6)
  - ALECHINSKY, Pierre, 1927- (Box 6)
  - BAES, Emile, 1879- (Box 6)
  - BEERS, Jan van, 1852- (Box 6)
  - BURY, Pol, 1922- (Box 6)
  - CARTE, Anto, 1886- (Box 6)
  - CLAYS, Emile, 1849-1924 (Box 6)
  - CLAYS, Paul Jean, 1819-1900 (Box 6)
  - CORNEILLE, 1922- (Box 6)
  - COURTENS, Franz, 1854- (Box 6)
  - DELVAUX, Paul, 1897-1994 (Box 6)
  - DONAS, Tour (Box 6)
  - ENSOR, James, 1860-1949 (Box 6–7)
  - FINCH, Alfred (Box 7)
  - GALLAIT, Louis, 1810-1887 (Box 7)
  - KNOPFF, Fernand, 1858- (Box 7)
  - LAERMANS, Eugene J.J., 1864- (Box 7)
  - LEMMEN, Georges, 1865-1916 (Box 7)
  - LEYS, Jan August Hendrick, 1815-1869 (Box 7)
  - MADOU, Jean Baptiste, 1796-1877 (Box 7)
  - MAGRITTE, Rene, 1898-1967 (Box 7)
  - MEUNIER, Constantin Emil, 1831-1905 (Box 7)
  - MORREN, George, 1868-1941 (Box 7)
  - OPSOMER, Isadore, 1878- (Box 7)
  - RYSSELBERGHE, Theo van, 1862-1926 (Box 7)
  - SAGA, Pietro de (Box 7)
  - SERVRANCK, Victor, 1897- (Box 7)
  - STEVENS, Alfred, 1817-1875 (Box 7)
  - STEVENS, Joseph Edward, ca. 1820-1892 (Box 7)
  - STOBBAERT, Jean Baptiste, 1838-1914 (Box 7)
  - TRUYS, Alexander, 1852- (Box 7)
  - THOMAS, Henry (Box 7)
  - VELDE, Henry van de, 1863-1957 (Box 7)
  - VELDE, Henry van de, 1863-1957 (Box 7)
  - WOUTERS, Rik, 1882-1916 (Box 7)
- Painting Britain (Box 7)
  - General (Box 7)
  - London (Box 7)
    - Wilton Diptych (Box 7)
  - 15th century (Box 7)
  - 16th century (Box 8)
  - 17th century (Box 8)
  - 18th century (Box 8)
  - 19th century (Box 8)
  - AGASSE, Jacque L., 1767-1849 (Box 8)
  - ALKEN, Henry, 1784-1851 (Box 8)
  - ALLAN, David, 1744-1796 (Box 8)
  - ALMA Tadema, Sir Lawrence, 1836-1912 (Box 8)
  - ANDRE, Major John, 1751-1781 (Box 8)
  - BACON, Sir Nathaniel, 1585-1627 (Box 8)
  - BARBER, Charles, 1783-1854 (Box 8)
  - BARLOW, F., 1626-1702 (Box 8)
  - BARTLETT, William Henry, 1809-1854 (Box 8)
  - BATEMAN, James, 1811-1897 (Box 8)
  - BEALE, Mary, 1633-1697 (Box 8)
  - BEARDSLEY, Aubrey Vincent, 1872-1898 (Box 8)
  - BEERBOHM, Max, 1892- (Box 8)
  - BELCHER, G.F. (Box 8)
  - BETTES, John, I, fl. 1545-1559 (Box 8)
  - BLAKE, William, 1757-1827 (Box 9)
    - Book of Job (Box 9)
    - Illustrations to Dante's Inferno (Box 9)
    - Illustrations to Paradise Lost (Box 9)
  - BONE, Muirhead, 1876- (Box 9)
  - BONINGTON, Richard Parkes, 1802-1828 (Box 9)
  - BOWLER, Henry, 1824-1903 (Box 9)
  - BRANGWYN, Sir Frank, 1867-1956 (Box 9)
  - BROCKHURST, Gerald L., 1890- (Box 9)
  - BRONTE, Patrick B. (Box 9)
  - BROOKING, Charles, 1723-1759 (Box 9)
  - BROOKS, Jon, 1944- (Box 9)
  - BROWN, Ford Madox, 1821-1893 (Box 9)
    - Manchester (Box 9)
    - Sydney (Box 9)
  - BROWN, John, 1752-1787 (Box 9)
  - BRUNAIS, Augustin (Box 9)
  - BURNE-JONES, Edward, 1833-1898 (Box 9)
    - Cambridge, MA (Box 9)
    - London (Box 9)
  - BURNEY, Edward, 1760-1848 (Box 10)
  - BURRA, Edward, 1905- (Box 10)
  - CALDERON, Philip Hermogenes, 1833-1898 (Box 10)
  - CLAUSEN, George, 1852-1944 (Box 10)
  - COLLINSON, James, 1825-1881 (Box 10)
  - COLQUHOUN, Robert, 1914- (Box 10)
  - CONDER, Charles, 1868-1909 (Box 10)
  - CONEY, John, 1786-1833 (Box 10)
  - CONSTABLE, John, 1776-1837 (Box 10)
    - Drawings (Box 10)
    - Paintings (Box 10)
      - Chicago (Box 10)
      - London (Box 10)
        - National Gallery (Box 10)
        - Victoria and Albert Museum (Box 10)
      - New Haven (Box 11)
      - New York (Box 11)
      - San Marino (Box 11)
      - Washington (Box 11)
  - COOPER, Samuel, 1609-1672 (Box 11)
  - COSWAY, Richard, 1742-1821 (Box 11)
  - COTES, Francis, 1726-1770 (Box 11)
  - COTES, Francis, 1726-1770 (Box 11)
  - COTES, Francis, 1726-1770 (Box 11)
  - COZENS, Alex, ca. 1710-1786 (Box 11)
  - COZENS, John Robert, 1752-1797 (Box 11)
  - CRANE, Walter, 1845-1915 (Box 11)
  - CRANE, Walter, 1845-1915 (Box 11)
  - DADD, Richard, 1817-1888 (Box 11)
  - DAHL, Michael, 1656-1743 (Box 11)
  - D' AGAR, C. (Box 11)
  - DANBY, Francis, 1793-1861 (Box 11)
  - DANCE, George, the Younger, 1741-1825 (Box 11)
  - DANCE, Nathaniel, 1787-1849 (Box 11)
  - DANDRIDGE, Bartholomew, fl. 1711-1750 (Box 11)
  - DANIELL, William, 1769-1837 (Box 11)
  - DE CRITZ, John, the Younger, 1600-1644 (Box 11)
  - DE HASSE (Box 11)
  - DEVIS, Arthur, 1712-787 (Box 12)
  - DIGBY, Simon, d. 1720 (Box 12)
  - DIGHTON, Robert, ca. 1752-1814 (Box 12)
  - DU MAURIER, George Louis Palmella Busson, 1834-1896 (Box 12)
  - DYCE, William, 1806-1864 (Box 12)
  - EASTLAKE, Charles Lock, 1793-1865 (Box 12)
  - ECCARDT, John Giles (Box 12)
  - EGG, Augustus Leopold, 1816-ca. 1863 (Box 12)
  - EGLEY, William Maw, fl. 1843-1898 (Box 12)
  - EPSTEIN, Jacob, 1880-1959 (Box 12)
  - ETTY, William, 1787-1849 (Box 12)
  - EWORTH, Hans, ca. 1525-after 1578 (Box 12)
  - FAITHORNE, William, 1656-ca. 1701 (Box 12)
  - FARINGTON, Joseph, 1747-1821 (Box 12)
  - FIELD, Robert (Box 12)
  - FLATMAN, Thomas, 1635-1688 (Box 12)
  - FLAXMAN, John, 1755-1826 (Box 12)
  - FLICKE, Gerlach, d. 1558 (Box 12)
  - FRITH, William Powell, 1819-1909 (Box 12)
  - FULLER, Isaac, 1606-1672 (Box 12)
  - FURSE, Charles, 1868-1904 (Box 12)
  - FUSELI, Henry, 1747-1825 (Box 12)
  - GAINSBOROUGH, Thomas, 1727-1788 (Box 12–13)
    - Drawings (Box 13)
    - Paintings (Box 13)
      - Private Collection (Box 13)
      - Birmingham (Box 13)
      - London (Box 13)
        - National Gallery (Box 13)
        - Wallace Collection (Box 13)
      - New York (Box 13)
        - Frick Collection (Box 13)
      - San Marino (Box 13)
      - Washington (Box 13)
  - GEDDES, Andrew, 1783-1844 (Box 14)
  - GERTLER, Mark, 1892-1939 (Box 14)
  - GILMAN, Harold, 1876-1919 (Box 14)
  - GIRTIN, Thomas, 1775-1802 (Box 14)
  - GORE, Spencer, 1878-1914 (Box 14)
  - GOWER, George, 16th century (Box 14)
  - GOWING, Lawrence (Box 14)
  - GRANT, Duncan, 1885-1978 (Box 14)
  - GRANT, Sir Francis, 1803-1878 (Box 14)
  - GREAVES, Walter, 1846-1930 (Box 14)
  - GREENAWAY, Kate, 1846-1901 (Box 14)
  - GREENHILL, John, ca. 1644-1676 (Box 14)
  - HAMILTON, Gawen, 1697-1737 (Box 14)
  - HAYDON, Benjamin Robert, 1786-1846 (Box 14)
  - HAYMAN, Francis, 1708-1776 (Box 14)
  - HERKOMER, Hubert von, 1849-1914 (Box 14)
  - HIGHMORE, Joseph, 1692-1780 (Box 14)
  - HILL. L. Raven, fl. 1915 (Box 14)
  - HILLIARD, Nicholas, ca. 1547-1619 (Box 14)
  - HODGES, Charles, 1764-1837 (Box 14)
  - HODGES, William, 1744-1797 (Box 14)
  - HODGKINS, Frances, 1871- (Box 14)
  - HOGARTH, William 1697-1764 (Box 14–15)
    - Drawings (Box 15)
    - Paintings (Box 15)
      - London (Box 15)
        - National Gallery (Box 15)
          - Marriage a la Mode (Box 14)
        - Soane Museum (Box 15)
        - Tate Gallery (Box 15)
      - New York (Box 15)
      - Worcester (Box 15)
  - HONE, Nathaniel, 1718-1784 (Box 15)
  - HOPPNER, John, 1758-1810 (Box 15)
  - HOSKINS, John, fl. 1620-1664 (Box 15)
  - HOWARD, Luke (Box 15)
  - HUDSON, Thomas, 1707-1779 (Box 15)
  - HUGHES, Arthur, 1832-1915 (Box 15)
  - HUNT, William Holman, 1827-1910 (Box 15)
    - Birmingham (Box 15)
    - London (Box 15)
    - Oxford (Box 15)
  - JOHN, Augustus, 1878-1961 (Box 15)
  - JOHN, Gwen, 1876-1939 (Box 15)
  - JONES, David, 1895- (Box 15)
  - KAUFMAN, Angelica, 1741-1807 (Box 15)
  - KEENE, Charles Samuel, 1823-1891 (Box 15)
  - KETTLE, Tilly, ca. 1734-1786 (Box 15)
  - KNELLER, Godfrey, baronet, 1642-1723 (Box 16)
    - London (Box 16)
  - KNIGHT, Laura, 1887-1970 (Box 16)
  - LAMB, Henry, 1885- (Box 16)
  - LAMBERT, George, 1710-1765 (Box 16)
  - LANCE, George (Box 16)
  - LANDSEER, Edwin Henry, 1802-1873 (Box 16)
  - LAROON, Marcelius, the Younger, 1679-1774 (Box 16)
  - LAVERY, John, 1858-1941 (Box 16)
  - LAWRENCE, Thomas, 1769-1830 (Box 16)
    - London (Box 16)
    - New York (Box 16)
    - San Marino (Box 16)
  - LEAR, Edward, 1812-1888 (Box 17)
  - LEIGHTON, Frederick, baron, 1830-1896 (Box 17)
  - LELY, Peter, 1618-1680 (Box 17)
  - LESLIE, Charles Robert, 1794-1859 (Box 17)
  - LEWIS, Wyndham, 1882-1957 (Box 17)
  - LINNELL, John, 1792-1882 (Box 17)
  - LINTON, James Bromgole, 1840-1916 (Box 17)
  - LOWRY, Laurence Stephen, 1887-1934 (Box 17)
  - MacDONALD, Margaret, 1865-1933 (Box 17)
  - MARK, Edouardo, 1817-1895 (Box 17)
  - MARSHALL, Alexander (Box 17)
  - MARSHALL, Ben, ca. 1767-1835 (Box 17)
  - MARTIN, John, 1789-1854 (Box 17)
  - MARTINEAU, Robert Braithwaite, 1826-1869 (Box 17)
  - MAY, Phil, 1864-1903 (Box 17)
  - MILLAIS, John Everett, 1829-1896 (Box 17)
    - London (Box 17)
  - MONAMY, Peter, ca. 1670-1749 (Box 17)
  - MOORE, Albert Joseph, 1841-1893 (Box 17)
  - MOORE, Henry, 1898-1986 (Box 17–18)
  - MORLAND, George, 1763-1804 (Box 18)
  - MORRIS, William, 1834-1896 (Box 18)
  - MORTIMER, John H., 1741-1779 (Box 18)
  - MULREADY, Michael, 1801-1889 (Box 18)
  - MULREADY, William, 1786-1863 (Box 18)
  - MUNNINGS, Alfred James, 1878-1959 (Box 18)
  - NASH, Joseph, the Elder, 1808-1878 (Box 18)
  - NASH, Paul, 1889-1946 (Box 18)
  - NEVINSON, Christopher, 1889-1946 (Box 18)
  - NICHOLSON, Ben, 1894- (Box 18)
  - NOLLEKENS, Joseph Francis, 1702-1748 (Box 18)
  - OLIVER, Isaac, ca. 1556-1617 (Box 18)
  - OPIE, John, 1761-1807 (Box 18)
  - ORCHARDSON, William Quiller, 1832-1910 (Box 18)
  - ORPEN, William, 1878-1931 (Box 18)
  - OWEN, William (Box 18)
  - PACK, Faithful Chris, 1759-1840 (Box 18–19)
  - PALMER, Samuel, 1805-1881 (Box 19)
  - PASMORE, Victor, 1908- (Box 19)
  - PATCH, Thomas, 1725-1782 (Box 19)
  - PEAKE, Robert, 1551-1619 (Box 19)
  - PENNY, Edward, 1714-1791 (Box 19)
  - PETTIE, John, 1839-1893 (Box 19)
  - PHILIPS, Charles, 1708-1747 (Box 19)
  - PIPER, John, 1903- (Box 19)
  - POLLARD, James, 1792-1867 (Box 19)
  - POYNTER, Edward John, 1836-1919 (Box 19)
  - PRINSEP, Valentin Cameron, 1838-1904 (Box 19)
  - PROCTOR, Dod (Box 19)
  - PROCTER, Ernest (Box 19)
  - PRYDE, James, 1869-1941 (Box 19)
  - RAEBURN, Sir Henry, 1756-1823 (Box 19)
    - Edinburgh (Box 19)
    - London (Box 19)
    - New York (Box 19)
    - Paris (Box 19)
    - Washington (Box 19)
  - RAMSAY, Allan, 1713-1784 (Box 19)
  - REINAGLE, Philip, 1749-1833 (Box 20)
  - REYNOLDS, Joshua, 1723-1792 (Box 20)
    - Olkham (Box 20)
    - London (Box 20)
      - Buckingham Palace (Box 20)
      - National Gallery (Box 20)
    - New Haven (Box 20)
    - New York (Box 20)
      - Frick Collection (Box 20)
    - Washington (Box 20)
  - RICHARDSON, Jonathon, 1665-1745 (Box 20)
  - RILEY, John, 1646-1691 (Box 20)
  - RIVIERE, Briton, 1840-1920 (Box 20)
  - ROBERTS, William, 1895- (Box 20–21)
  - ROBERTSON, Andrew, 1777-1845 (Box 21)
  - ROBINSON, Andrew (Box 21)
  - ROGERS, Claude (Box 21)
  - ROMNEY, George, 1734-1802 (Box 21)
    - London (Box 21)
    - New York (Box 21)
    - Washington (Box 21)
  - ROSSETTI, Dante Gabriele, 1828-1882 (Box 22)
    - Cambridge (Box 22)
    - London (Box 22)
      - Tate Gallery (Box 22)
  - ROTHENSTEIN, William, 1872-1945 (Box 22)
    - New York (Box 22)
  - ROWLANDSON, Thomas, 1756-1827 (Box 22)
  - RUSKIN, John, 1819-1900 (Box 22)
  - SALISBURY, Frank, 1874- (Box 22)
  - SALMON, Robert, 1780-1840 (Box 22)
  - SANDBY, Paul, 1725-1809 (Box 22)
  - SANDYS, Frederick, 1829-1904 (Box 22)
  - SCOTT, Samuel, 1703-1792 (Box 22)
  - SCOTT, William Bell, 1811-1890 (Box 22)
  - SEDDON, Thomas, III, 1821-1856 (Box 22)
  - SEEMAN, Enoch, 1694-1744 (Box 22)
  - SERRES, Dominic, 1722-1798 (Box 22)
  - SHEPPARD, William (Box 22)
  - SICKER, Walter Richard, 1860-1942 (Box 23)
  - SIDDAL, Elizabeth Eleanor, 1829-1862 (Box 23)
  - SIMPSON, William, 1823-1889 (Box 23)
  - SIMS, Charles, 1873-1928 (Box 23)
  - SINGLETON, Henry, 1766-1839 (Box 23)
  - SMITH, Matthew, 1879- (Box 23)
  - SPENCER, Stanley, 1891-1959 (Box 23)
  - STANNARD, Joseph, 1797-1830 (Box 23)
  - STEER, Philip Wilson, 1860-1942 (Box 23)
  - STREATER, Robert, 1624-1680 (Box 23)
  - STREETES, William, fl. 1555 (Box 23)
  - STUBBS, George, 1724-1806 (Box 23)
  - SUTHERLAND, Graham Vivian, 1903-1980 (Box 23)
  - TAIT, Robert (Box 23)
  - TALFOURD, Field (Box 23)
  - TENNANT, Dorothy (Lady Stanley) (Box 23)
  - THORHILL, James, 1695-1734 (Box 23)
  - THRUMTON, T. (Box 23)
  - TONKS, Henry, 1862-1937 (Box 23)
  - TOWNE, Francis, ca. 1739-1816 (Box 23)
  - TUKE, Henry Scott, 1858- (Box 24)
  - TUNNARD, John, 1900- (Box 24)
  - TURNER, Joseph Mallord, William, 1775-1851 (Box 24)
    - Paintings (Box 24)
      - London (Box 24)
        - National Gallery (Box 24)
        - Tate Gallery (Box 24)
      - New Haven (Box 24)
      - New York (Box 24)
        - Frick Collection (Box 24)
      - Washington (Box 24)
  - UNDERWOOD, Leon G.C. (Box 24)
  - VIDAL, Emeric Essex, 1791-1861 (Box 24)
  - WALKER, Frederick, 1841-1874 (Box 24)
  - WALKER, Robert, ca. 1600-ca. 1659 (Box 24)
  - WARD, Edward Matthew, 1816-1879 (Box 24)
  - WARD, James, 1769-1859 (Box 24)
  - WATTS, Georges Frederick, 1817-1904 (Box 24)
    - London (Box 24)
  - WEBSTER, Thomas, 1800-1886 (Box 25)
  - WELLS, Henry Tanworth, 1828-1903 (Box 25)
  - WESTALL, Richard, 1765-1836 (Box 25)
  - WHEATLEY, Francis, 1747-1801 (Box 25)
  - WHITE, Robert, 1645-1703 (Box 25)
  - WILKIE, David, 1785-1841 (Box 25)
  - WILSON, Richard, 1713-1782 (Box 25)
    - London (Box 25)
  - WINDUS, William, 1822-1907 (Box 25)
  - WINT, Peter de, 1784-1849 (Box 25)
  - WOOD, John (Box 25)
  - WOOTTON, John, 1678?-1765 (Box 25)
  - WRIGHT, John Michael, 1617-1694 (Box 25)
  - WRIGHT, Joseph, of Derby, 1734-1797 (Box 25)
  - ZOFFANY, Johann Joseph, 1733-1810 (Box 25)
- Painting Canada (Box 25)
  - CLARENCE, Gagnon, 1881- (Box 25)
  - LAWREN S. Harris (Box 25)
  - RIOPELLE, Jean-Paul, 1923-2002 (Box 25)
- Painting Denmark (Box 26)
  - CARSTENS, Asmus Jakob, 1754-1798 (Box 26)
  - ECKERSBERG, Christoffer, W., 1783-1853 (Box 26)
  - JORN, Asger, 1914-1973 (Box 26)
  - PEDERSEN, Carl-Henning, 1913- (Box 26)
  - RORBYE, Martinus C.W., 1803-1848 (Box 26)
- Painting Flanders (Box 26)
  - 15th century (Box 26)
    - Verhouten Tryptych (Box 26)
    - Master of the Ufe of S. Gudule (Box 26)
  - 16th century (Box 26)
  - 17th century (Box 26)
  - BEAUMETZ, Jean de, 1390-1396, and asst (Box 26)
  - BELLECHOSE, Henri, fl. 1415-d. ca. 1445 (Box 26)
  - BENEDETTI, Andrea, fl. ca. 1640-1660 (Box 26)
  - BENSON, Ambrosius, 1515-1550 (Box 26)
  - BEUCKELAER, Joachim, 1530-1575 (Box 26)
  - BLONDEL, Lancelot, 1495-1581 (Box 26)
  - BOEL, Peter, 1622-1674 (Box 26)
  - BOSCH, Hieronymus, ca. 1450-1516 (Box 26)
    - Berlin (Box 26)
    - Brussels (Box 26)
    - Escorial (Box 26)
    - Frankfurt (Box 27)
    - Ghent (Box 27)
    - Lisbon (Box 27)
    - London (Box 27)
    - Madrid (Box 27)
      - Garden of Earthly Delights (Box 27)
    - New Haven (Rabinowitz) (Box 27)
    - New York (Box 27)
    - Paris (Box 27)
    - Philadelphia (Box 27)
    - Rotterdam (Box 27)
    - Venice (Box 27)
    - Vienna (Box 27)
    - Washington (Box 27)
  - BOUTS, Aelbrecht, ca. 1460?-1549 (Box 27)
  - BOUTS, Dieric, ca. 1415-1475 (Box 27–28)
    - Berlin (Box 28)
    - Bruges (Box 28)
    - Brussels (Box 28)
    - London (Box 28)
    - Louvain (Lowen) (Box 28)
    - Madrid (Box 28)
    - Munich (Box 28)
    - New York (Box 28)
    - Paris (Box 28)
    - Philadelphia (Box 28)
  - BRILL, Paul (Box 28)
  - BROUWER, Adriaen, ca. 1605-1638 (Box 28)
  - BRUEGHEL, Jan, the elder, 1568-1625 (Box 28)
    - Vienna (Box 28)
  - BRUEGHEL, Pieter, the elder, ca. 1525-1569 (Box 28)
    - Drawings (Box 28)
    - Paintings (Box 28)
      - Antwerp (Box 28)
      - Berlin (Box 28)
      - Brussels (Box 28)
      - Budapest (Box 28)
      - Darmstadt (Box 28)
      - Detroit (Box 28)
      - London (Box 29)
      - Madrid (Box 29)
      - Munich (Box 29)
      - Naples (Box 29)
      - New York (Box 29)
      - Paris (Box 29)
      - Prague (Box 29)
      - Rotterdam (Box 29)
      - Vienna (Box 29)
        - Contest between Carnival and Lent (Box 29)
        - Hunters in the Snow (Box 29)
        - Road to Calvary (Box 29)
        - Tower of Babel (Box 29)
      - Washington (Box 29)
  - BRUEGHEL, Pieter, the younger, ca. 1534-ca. 1637 (Box 29)
  - CAMPIN, Robert, ca. 1375-1444 (Box 30)
    - Berlin (Box 30)
    - Dijon (Box 30)
    - Frankfurt (Box 30)
    - London (Box 30)
    - Madrid (Box 30)
    - New York (Box 30)
  - CHRISTUS, Petrus, ca. 1410-ca. 1475 (Box 30)
    - Berlin (Box 30)
    - Brussels (Box 30)
    - Detroit (Box 30)
    - London (Box 30)
    - Lugano (Box 30)
    - New York (Box 30)
    - Paris (Box 30)
    - Washington (Box 30)
  - CLERCK, Hendrick de (Box 30)
  - CLEVE, Joos van, d. ca. 1540 (Box 31)
  - COTER, Colijn de, 1467?-ca. 1506 (Box 31)
  - DALEM, Cornelis van (Box 31)
  - DARET, Jacquez, 1404-1468 (Box 31)
  - DAVID, Gerard, ca. 1460-1523 (Box 31)
    - Bruges (Box 31)
    - Brussels (Box 31)
    - Cambridge (see van der Weyden) (Box 31)
    - Frankfurt (Box 31)
    - Genoa (Box 31)
    - Hamburg (Box 31)
    - London (Box 31)
    - Munich (Box 31)
    - New York (Box 31)
      - Bache Collection (Box 31)
      - Frick Collection (Box 31)
    - Paris (Box 31)
    - Rouen (Box 31)
    - Washington (Box 31)
  - DIEPENBEECK, A., 1596-1675 (Box 31)
  - FLORIS, Frans (Box 31)
  - FRANCK, Pauwels, 1540-1596 (Box 31)
  - FRANKEN, Ambrosius, 1544-1618 (Box 31)
  - FRANKEN, Frans I, 1542-1616 (Box 31)
  - FRANKEN, Frans II, 1581-1642 (Box 31)
  - GEERTEEN, tot sint Jans (Box 31)
  - GHEERAERTS, Marcus the younger, 1561-1635 (Box 31)
  - GHENT, Joos van (see Joos van Ghent) (Box 31)
  - GOES, Hugo van der, ca. 1440-1482 (Box 31)
    - Baltimore (Box 31)
    - Berlin (Box 31)
    - Bruges (Box 31)
    - Brussels (Box 31)
    - Florence (Box 32)
    - Frankfurt (Box 32)
    - Hollyrood (Box 32)
    - New York (Box 32)
    - Vienna (Box 32)
    - Wilton House (Box 32)
  - HAECHT, William van (Box 32)
  - HELMONT, Lucas van Gassel, ca. 1480-ca. 1555 (Box 32)
  - HOEFNAGEL, Joris (Georg), 1542-1600 (Box 32)
  - HUYS, Pieter (Box 32)
  - HUYSMANS, Jacob, 1633-1696 (Box 32)
  - ISENBRANDT, Adriaen (Box 32)
  - JOOS van Ghent (Justus) (Box 32)
  - JORDAENS, Jacob, 1593-1678 (Box 32)
    - Drawings (Box 32)
    - Paintings (Box 32)
      - Brussels (Box 32)
      - Madrid (Box 32)
      - Paris (Box 32)
  - LOMBARD, Lambert, 1506-1566 (Box 33)
  - [MABUSE], Jan Gossaert, ca. 1478-1532 (Box 33)
    - Berlin (Box 33)
    - London (Box 33)
    - Madrid (Box 33)
    - Munich (Box 33)
    - New York (Box 33)
    - Palermo (Box 33)
    - Paris (Box 33)
    - Prague (Box 33)
    - Vienna (Box 33)
  - MARIS, Jacobus (Box 33)
  - MASSYS, Cornelius, 1510-1580 (Box 33)
  - MASSYS, Jan, 1509-1595 (Box 33)
  - MASSY, Quinten, 1466-1530 (Box 33)
    - Antwerp (Box 33)
    - Berlin (Box 33)
    - Brussels (Box 33)
    - New York (Box 33)
    - Paris (Box 33)
    - Posen (Box 33)
    - Vierhouten (Box 33)
  - MASTER of Flemalle (Box 33)
  - MEMLING, Hans, ca. 1430-1494 (Box 33–34)
    - Anvers (Box 34)
    - Berlin (Box 34)
    - Bruges (Box 34)
      - S. John's Hospital (Box 34)
        - S. Ursula Shrine (Box 34)
    - Brussels (Box 34)
    - London (Box 34)
    - Madrid (Box 34)
    - Munich (Box 34)
    - New York (Box 34)
    - Paris (Box 34)